Observe the periorbital area, eyelids and eyes, noting any abnormalities.
observation-02
Then perform a magnified examination. Prepare the Arclight by selecting the brightest light setting.
observation-03
Hold the device close to your eye. Slowly approach the patient's right eye first until it is in focus.
observation-04
Ask the patient to look right, then left.
observation-05
Then ask them to look up and down while gently holding their eyelids. Note the different structures seen, thinking of them in groups.
structures-01
The first group includes the upper and lower eyelashes and lid margins.
structures-02
The second includes the conjunctiva and sclera,
structures-03
including the lower fornix.
structures-04
The third group is the cornea,
structures-05
and its junction with the sclera, called the limbus,
structures-06
as well as the pupil, which is surrounded by the iris.
conditions-01
These are pictures of different conditions. Take time to examine with your Arclight.
chamber-depth-01
The anterior chamber is the space between the cornea and the iris.
chamber-depth-02
By shining the light from the temporal side, the depth of the anterior chamber can be assessed.
chamber-depth-03
A nasal shadow can suggest a shallow chamber. Refer.
fluorescein-application
Use a fluorescein strip or a Minims dropper to apply fluorescein to the eye.
fluorescein-01
Select the blue light and inspect the cornea.
fluorescein-02
Areas of epithelial loss and disease will be highlighted. Record the site and size of these areas.
lid-eversion-grip
Gently pinch and hold the eyelashes of the upper lid with your thumb and index finger.
lid-eversion-01
Place a cotton bud on the upper eyelid, use it as a fulcrum and turn the lid upwards.
lid-eversion-02
Hold the lid everted and inspect its inner surface, first with the naked eye,
lid-eversion-03
then bring in the Arclight for a magnified view.